在选举中。
in the elections.
en las elecciones.
因为他给我们留下了一个壮观的到来
because he has left us a spectacular arrival
porque nos ha dejado un llegado también espectacular
非常专业
very professional
muy profesionales
帕奎因。
Paquin.
Paquín.
有一天，在规则活动中心帕拉迪斯波电台，我想问你......
And someday at the Rule Active Center Paradispo Radio I would like to ask you...
Y algún día en la Regla Centro Activo Paradispo Radio me gustaría pedirte...
对巴勃罗·迪巴拉的新电话进行反思，并借此机会问问自己是否……
a reflection about this new call to Pablo Dybala and take the opportunity to ask yourself if...
una reflexión acerca de esta nueva convocatoria a Pablo Dybala y aprovechar para preguntarte si...
你重视留在意大利罗马比赛的决定吗？
Did you value the decision to stay and compete in Italy, Roma?
¿Le valoraste la decisión de quedarse a competir en Italia, la Roma?
电话...
The call...
La convocatoria...
这与他留在意大利无关。
and it has no relation to the fact that he stayed in Italy.
y no tiene relación con que se haya quedado en Italia.
他在联盟之外的球场上做了什么
what he does on the field beyond the league
lo que hace dentro de la cancha más allá de la liga
他对自己小时候的身份非常了解，他留在了他非常热爱的俱乐部，抛开了其他事情。
very well about what he is as a kid and he has stayed in the club that he loves so much and leaving aside other things.
muy bien de lo que es él como pibe y se ha quedado en el club que tanto quiere y dejando de lado otras cosas.
但电话是足球认为球队会
but the call was football thinking that the team would
pero la convocatoria ha sido futbolística pensando que el equipo lo
门
the door
la puerta.
早上好，Leonelli，红色广播电台的 Gustavo Charroche。
Good morning Leonelli, Gustavo Charroche for Radio La Red.
Buen día Leonelli, Gustavo Charroche para Radio La Red.
由于他有一点不舒服，他明天可以参加比赛，如果你对其他方面有疑问
He will be able to play tomorrow due to a small discomfort he has and the other if you have questions about
va a poder jugar mañana por una pequeña molestia que tiene y la otra si es que tenés interrogantes en
或者做第一部分的训练，他已经能做到了。
or do a first part of the training, he has been able to do it.
o hacer una primera parte del entrenamiento, él lo ha podido hacer.
根据他的情况，这不会改变我们的比赛方式，因为最终
Based on how he is, it doesn't change the way we play much because in the end
en base a como esté él no es que nos cambia mucho la manera de jugar porque al final
我们将继续玩同样的游戏。
We will continue playing the same.
Seguiremos jugando igual.
我不知道球队的其他人怎么样，或多或少已经决定了。
I don't know how the rest of the team is, it's more or less decided.
No sé cómo está el resto del equipo, más o menos está decidido.
因为水质不好。
Because the water is bad.
Porque está mal la agua.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
球迷之间的关系发生了180度的转变。
the 180 degree change in the relationship between the fans.
el cambio de 180 grados en la relación de los hinchas.
在一个非常关键的时刻，当你看到...
at a very critical moment and when you saw that...
en un momento muy crítico y cuando viste que...
对你来说，对吗？
for you, right?
por vos, ¿no?
比方说，我让你投入了多少钱？
Let's say, how much did I make you put in?
digamos, ¿cuánto te hice que poner vos?
特别是与安赫尔有关，为阿根廷队提供了实现所有目标所需的机会。
especially in relation to Ángel to give this opportunity that the Argentine teams needed to achieve all their objectives.
en especial en relación a Ángel para dar esta oportunidad que necesitaban las selecciones argentinas para lograr todos los objetivos.
我想问的另一件事是阿根廷的情况在历史上发生过。
The other thing I wanted to ask you is where in history the Argentine situation occurs.
Lo otro que quería preguntarte es en qué lugar de la historia la situación argentina ocurre.
他从未停止过想要来到这里。
He has never stopped wanting to be here.
nunca ha dejado de querer estar acá
有一段时间他没有跟我一起来，而且时间很短。
There was a time when he didn't come with me and it was a very short time.
hubo un momento que conmigo no venía y fue un tiempo muy corto
过了山口，他继续和我们一起逃亡，又是一个，已经被
the pass, he continued fleeing with us and was one more and has been
el paso, él siguió huyendo con nosotros y fue uno más y ha estado
上场30分钟，他没有上场，他打了90分钟，他打了60分钟，他总是为我们做他的事情。
30 minutes on the field, he has not played, he has played 90, he has played 60 and he has always done his thing for us.
30 minutos dentro de la cancha, no ha jugado, ha jugado 90, ha jugado 60 y siempre ha portado lo suyo para nosotros.
它具有不可估量的价值。
It has incalculable value.
Tiene un valor incalculable.
从未放下过双臂，从未有过难看的表情……
of never having lowered his arms, of never having a bad face...
de no haber bajado los brazos nunca, de no tener nunca una mala cara...
非常清楚穿着这件球衣踢球意味着什么，这就是与队友分享的内容
to know very well what it means to play with this shirt and this is what to share with his teammates
de saber muy bien lo que representa jugar con esta camiseta y así es lo compartir a sus compañeros
所以我们没有从他那里得到任何优点，无论如何，或者在任何情况下从他的同事那里得到......
So we have no merit from him and in any case or in any case from his colleagues who have...
Entonces nosotros no tenemos ningún mérito de él y en cualquier caso o en todo caso de sus compañeros que lo han...
他们已经能够理解了，但在台阶上我不知道如何说对不起
They have been able to understand it and on the step I didn't know how to say sorry
lo han sabido entender y en el escalón no sabía decirte perdón
毫无疑问，除了历史上的冠军之外，阿根廷还拥有过最好的
of the best, without a doubt, beyond the titles in history, Argentina has had
de los mejores, sin duda, más allá de los títulos de la historia, Argentina ha tenido
我不能不尊重很多球员，他们在整个历史上都度过了一段美好的时光。
and I can't disrespect a lot of players, they have had a great time playing throughout their history.
y no puedo faltar el respeto a un montón de jugadores, ha tenido enorme jugar en toda su historia.
还有人会觉得以前的也很好，也会有人觉得现在的也很好。
And there will be people who will think that those from before were also very good, there are people who will think that those from now are very good.
Y habrá gente que pensará que los de antes también eran muy buenos, hay gente que pensará que los de ahora son muy buenos.
他在伟大球员的历史上是多么伟大，这最近给我们带来了巨大的快乐。
how great he is in the history of great players and that has given us enormous joy in recent times.
lo buenísimo que está dentro de la historia de los grandes jugadores y que nos ha dado una alegría enorme en estos últimos tiempos.
谢谢您，先生。
Thank you, sir.
Gracias, señor.
是的，这是 Daniel Octavio Cotelis，他在 Hugo 上制作了一张专辑。
Yes, here is Daniel Octavio Cotelis, who makes an album on Hugo.
Sí, acá Daniel Octavio Cotelis, que realiza un disco en Hugo.
别忘了询问一些新面孔，昨天我们正在和锡诺尼亚公民交谈……
Don't forget to ask about some new faces, yesterday we were talking to Sinonian citizens...
Se quito preguntar por algunas caras nuevas, ayer estuvimos hablando con los ciudadanos sinónicos...
现在我们也许可以加入费尔南德斯的行列。
And now we can perhaps join this Fernández.
Y ya nos podemos sumar quizás a este fernández.
通过一点一点地或突然地与他们交谈，他们可以在 30 分钟内完成他们的过程，如你所见，还有一个简短的短片
easier by talking to them little by little or suddenly they can do their process in 30 minutes as you see it and a short short
más fáciles hablándoles de a poco o de pronto pueden en 30 minutos hacer su proceso como lo veis y una cortita breve
关于 AFA 发起的一项关于非歧视的运动。
about a campaign launched by AFA about non-discrimination.
sobre una campaña que lanzó AFA acerca de la no discriminación.
我的意思是，我认为这很重要，请您反思一下食谱。
I mean, I think it's important and I ask you to reflect on the recipe, please.
Digo, creo que es importante y le pido una reflexión al receto, por favor.
谢谢。
Gracias.
首先我从新的照明开始，因为最后
First I start with the new lighting because in the end
Primero arranco con la nueva iluminación porque al final
我们都受到了伤害，这是一个我们已经知道的问题......
We are all harmed, it is an issue that we already know that...
Nos perjudicamos todos, es un tema que ya sabemos que...
必须认真对待它，我们是确保这种情况的主要责任者。
that it must be treated seriously and we are the main responsible for ensuring that this is the case.
que hay que tratarlo con seriedad y nosotros somos los principales responsables de que así sea.
人们都知道。
that people are aware.
de que la gente sea consciente.
并且他会一视同仁地与他的团队一起谋求利益。
and that he goes to the interest with his team without discriminating.
y que vaya al interés con su equipo sin discriminar.
除了因为这个原因明天我们比赛的人数会减少之外，真正重要的是......
Beyond the fact that we will play tomorrow with fewer people for that reason, the really important thing is that...
Más allá de que nosotros juguemos mañana con menos gente por eso, lo realmente importante es que...
不存在歧视。
that there is no discrimination.
que no haya discriminación.
在我们生活的时代，这已经没有任何意义了。
It doesn't make sense anymore in the times we live in.
No tiene sentido más en la época que vivimos.
这没有道理。
It doesn't make sense.
No tiene sentido.
还有关于新孩子的另一件事......
And the other thing about the new kids...
Y lo otro de los chicos nuevos...
现在，如果我们认为有必要，他们就会参与其中，他们就是为此而存在的，我们在每一个项目中都告诉过他们这一点。
Now they will be part if we believe it is necessary, they are there for that and we told them that in each one.
Ahora formarán parte si creemos que sea necesario, están para eso y eso se lo dijimos a ellos en cada uno.
我们已经说过了，他们在这里是因为我们
that we have spoken and they are here because we
que hemos hablado y están acá porque nos
他们不是来看看他们如何与国家队一起训练，而是我们相信他们可以为我们做出贡献
They are not there to see how they train with the national team but rather we believe that they can contribute to us
no están para ver cómo se entrenan con la selección sino que creemos que pueden aportarnos
基于游戏的内容以及我们对他们可以玩的游戏的看法。
Based on what the game will be and what we see of the game they can play.
en base a lo que será el partido y a lo que veamos del partido pueden jugar.
毫无疑问，因为他们正在展示这一点，因为他们很好，我认为这是一个......的时刻。
without a doubt because they are showing it, because they are well and I think it is a moment for...
sin duda porque lo están demostrando, porque están bien y creo que es un momento para...
能够欣赏这些家伙并让他们穿着衬衫看起来很酷。
to be able to enjoy those guys and make them look cool with the shirt.
para poder disfrutar de esos chicos y que sumen venudos con la camiseta.
这里是西班牙广播电台的马科斯·杜兰。
Over here, Marcos Durán from Radio de España.
Por acá, Marcos Durán de Radio de España.
四年前的二月我们在马德里做了一次采访
Four years ago we did an interview in Madrid in February
Hace cuatro años hicimos una entrevista en Madrid en febrero
2019 年美洲杯之后的 A2K20 告诉我，你告诉我两个至上，阿根廷需要获胜。
and A2K20 after the 2019 Copa América told me, you told me two supremacies, that Argentina needs to win.
y el A2K20 después de la Copa América 2019 me decía, me dijiste dos supremacias, que Argentina necesita ganar.
他们需要获胜，在赢得了他们赢得的一切之后，这一点一直困扰着我。
They need to win and that stuck with me after having won everything they won.
necesitan ganar y a mi me quedo grabado eso después de haber ganado todo lo que ganaron
您认为阿根廷现在需要什么才能继续增长？
What do you think Argentina needs now to continue growing?
¿Vos qué crees que necesita ahora Argentina para seguir creciendo?
我不记得告诉过你你需要什么。
I don't remember telling you that you needed anything.
No me acuerdo que te haya dicho que necesitabas nada.
我必须回顾一下，但重要的是...
I have to review, but the important thing...
Tengo que repasar, pero lo importante...
它总是在竞争而不是获胜，总是......
It is always competing more than winning, always being...
Es siempre competir más que ganar, siempre estar...
团队和他们的队友看到其他人竞争并且想要继续
that the team and their teammates see the other who competes and who wants to continue
que el equipo y sus compañeros vean al otro que compite y que tiene ganas de seguir
并且对手看到我们想要继续。
and that the rival sees that we want to continue.
y que el rival vea que tenemos ganas de seguir.
最终他赢得了伟大的胜利，但重要的是......
In the end he won great, but it is important that...
Al final después si ganaba buenísimo, pero es importante que...
在一个人移动的环境中，在这个例子中是在国家队，
that in the environment where one moves, in this case in the national team,
que en el ambiente donde uno se mueve, en este caso en la selección,
大家都看到了一个方向，这个方向就是继续最大限度的竞争。
Everyone sees that there is a direction and the direction is to continue competing to the maximum.
todos vean que hay una dirección y la dirección es seguir compitiendo al máximo.
它永远不会丢失，而我昨天告诉他的话，一会儿……
It will never be lost and what I told him yesterday, in a moment...
No va a ser por perdido nunca y lo que le dije ayer, en un momento...
我和他们交谈并告诉他们我们现在在做什么。
I spoke to them and told them what we were doing now.
Les hablé y les dije que qué hacíamos ahora.
我们正要回家。
We were returning home.
Nos volvíamos para casa.
我说的一点点。
A little bit what I said.
Un poco lo que dije.
去年我想，当你开始工作并取得一些成就时......
Last year I think, when you come to work and achieve something...
El año pasado creo, cuando uno llega en su trabajo y logra algo...
第二天你必须起床去上班，我们也做同样的事情
something good the next day you have to get up and go to work and we do the same
algo bueno al otro día tienes que levantarse y ir a trabajar y nosotros lo mismo
更重要的是，他们不仅在国家队踢球，而且还在俱乐部里燃烧。
and more so because they not only play in the National Team but also burn in their clubs.
y más ellos porque ellos no solo juegan en la Selección sino también queman en sus clubes.
因此，要进入国家队，他们必须为俱乐部打好比赛，他们必须表现出色
So to be in the national team they have to play well for their clubs, they have to be good
entonces para estar en la selección tienen que jugar bien en sus clubes, tienen que estar bien
所以他们不能放松，我总是在他们穿的时候这么说。
So they can't relax and I've always said it when they wear it.
o sea que no se pueden relajar y lo he dicho siempre que lo llevan
在他们的 DNA 中，竞争，永远处于最佳状态
in their DNA, to compete, to always be at their best
en su ADN, de competir, de estar siempre al máximo
它们可能很小并且不会改变。
possible performance that they are tiny and that is not going to change.
rendimiento posible de que son chiquititos y eso no le va a cambiar.
如果有一个我不理解的人发生了变化，我认为是这个团体本身。
If there is someone that I don't understand, that changes, I think it is the group itself.
Si hay alguno que no lo entiendo, que cambia, yo creo que es el propio grupo.
我们或多或少都有一个想法，团体本身就会让我们放松。
We more or less have an idea, the group itself will let us relax.
Ya más o menos tenemos una idea, el propio grupo nos lo dejará que se relaje.
然后我们将在那里做出适当的决定。
and then we will be there to make the appropriate decision.
y después estaremos nosotros a tomar la decisión oportuna.
他们没有向我展示这一点，然后你可以赢，你可以输，但是......
They don't show me that and then you can win, you can lose, but...
no me demuestran eso y después se puede ganar, se puede perder, pero...
表现出继续想要竞争的意愿，我认为这是最重要的。
The demonstration of continuing to want to compete, which I think is the most important thing of all.
La demostración de seguir queriendo competir, que creo que es lo más importante de todo.
如果他赢了，从逻辑上讲，一切都会被放大。
and then if he wins, logically everything is magnified.
y después si gana lógicamente todo se magnifica.
你好，莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Hello Lionel, how are you doing?
Hola Lionel, ¿cómo te va?
这就是为什么同事最近问到关于新面孔的问题，就像疯狂的问题一样，我问你关于给予他们的做法。
That's why the question that the colleague recently asked about the new faces, and like the crazy one, I asked you about practices of giving them.
Por eso la pregunta que hizo recién el colega sobre las caras nuevas, y como el locino te pregunto por prácticas de darlos.
后续进展如何？
How has the follow-up process been?
¿Cómo ha sido el proceso de seguimiento?
当轮到他增加上场时间时，你认为他能为球队做出什么贡献？
What do you think he can contribute to the team when it's his turn to add minutes?
¿Qué crees que le puede aportar al equipo cuando le toque sumar minutos?
嗯，他已经被预选过几次了，最后他没有来。
Well, he has already been preselected on some occasions and in the end he has not come.
Bueno, ha estado ya preseleccionado en alguna ocasión y al final no ha venido.
我们相信现在是一个拥有它、近距离了解它的好机会。
We believe that now is a good opportunity to have it, to get to know it up close.
Creemos que ahora es una buena oportunidad para tenerlo, para conocerlo de cerca.
今天，在 Leo 和 Ángel 缺席的情况下，球队需要一点……
The team today, in the absence of Leo and Ángel, needed a little...
El equipo hoy ante la ausencia de Leo, de Ángel, necesitaba un poco...
进攻流并结识那些……的人
offensive flow and meet people who...
de caudal ofensivo y conocer gente que...
他处于一个很好的水平，我们不知道，但我们希望他能够满足......
that he is at a good level, that we do not know and we want him to meet...
que está en buen nivel, que no conocemos y queremos que él reúne...
在有效的条件下，它有很好的运动，它关联得很好
with the conditions that are valid, it has very good movements, it associates well
con las condiciones que son válidas, tiene muy buenos movimientos, se asocia bien
打好球是我们首先看到的，它可以给我们带来东西。
play ball well and it is what we see first and it can give us things.
jugar bien a la pelota y es lo que primero vemos y nos puede aportar cosas.
教练，你好吗？
Coach, how are you?
Entrenador, ¿cómo están?
哈维尔·阿帕里西奥.
Javier Aparicio.
我们为萨尔塔、为阿里亚斯而活。
We are live for Salta, for Arias.
Estamos en vivo para Salta, para Arias.
Tico 10，我想问你两件事，你和 Nibala 真正谈论过她的未来吗？
And Tico 10, I wanted to ask you two things, did you have any real talk with Nibala about her future?
Y Tico 10, te quería preguntar dos cosas, ¿tuviste alguna charla verdadera con Nibala acerca de su futuro?
如果你得到了，他们就会谈论它。
If you got it, they talked about it.
si lo consigaste hablaron de eso
好吧，考虑到缺席和即将发生的事情，这个问题已经得到了回答
and well, the question is already answered taking into account the absences and what is coming
y bueno, la pregunta ya está repanida teniendo en cuenta las ausencias y lo que se viene
如果你再考虑一下一起或单独唱歌或演奏的可能性，你会如何处理？
If you think again about the possibility of singing or playing together or separately, how are you handling that?
Si volvés a pensar en la posibilidad de lautar o jugar juntos o separados, ¿cómo vas manejando eso?
谢谢。
Gracias.
好吧，关于巴勃罗和他的移情的话题......
Well, on the subject of Pablo and his transference...
Bueno, sobre el tema de Pablo y su transferencia...
我没有参与，只有当兄弟们被传唤时，我们才问他是否愿意留下来。
I didn't get involved, only when the brothers were summoned did we ask him if he would stay.
No me metí, solo cuando los hermanos estaban convocados le preguntamos si se quedaba.
但我们从来没有参与过球员的决定，我们也不会参与其中，他们就是决定
but we never got involved in the players' decisions nor are we going to get involved, they are decisions
pero nunca nos metimos en las decisiones de los jugadores ni nos vamos a meter, son decisiones
个人的，在很多情况下是足球决定，在其他情况下也是人生决定。
personal, in many cases football decisions, in other cases also life decisions.
personales, en muchos casos decisiones futbolísticas, en otros casos decisiones también de vida.
我们不会介入，因为我们都经历过这种情况。
and we are not going to get involved because we have all been in that situation.
y no nos vamos a meter porque hemos estado todos en esa situación.
也许这可能更令人困惑。
and maybe it's probably more confusing.
y a lo mejor es a lo mejor confundirlo más.
所以这个决定是你的，而且......
So that decision was yours and...
Así que esa decisión ha sido suya y...
欢迎，这对他更好，我认为他很高兴。
Welcome, it's better for him and I think he's happy.
Bienvenido sea, es mejor para él y creo que está contento.
至于劳塔罗和朱利安……
And in relation to Lautaro and Julián...
Y con relación a Lautaro y Julián...
这是整个杯赛的问题，这是常见的问题，我总是会回答同样的问题。
It was the question of the entire Cup, it was the usual question and I will always answer the same thing.
Fue la pregunta de toda la Copa, fue la pregunta de siempre y voy a responder siempre lo mismo.
一起玩过 可以一起玩 可以不一起玩 我们就看
have played together can play together may not play together we depend
han jugado juntos pueden jugar juntos pueden no jugar juntos dependemos
关于我们想如何比赛有很多，但很明显我们可以一起比赛。
a lot about how we want to play, but it is clear that we can play together.
mucho de cómo queremos jugar, pero es evidente que podemos jugar juntos.
他们已经做到了，我们相信
They have already done it and we believe that
ya lo han hecho y creemos que
这取决于我们将要面对的对手或者当时每个人的情况
that will depend on the rival we are going to face or also the circumstance of each one at the time
que dependerá del rival que vamos a afrontar o también la circunstancia de cada uno en el momento
这取决于很多事情，但他们是否能够按照逻辑进行比赛。
It depends on many things, but if they can play logically.
Depende de muchas cosas, pero si pueden jugar lógico.
这里是莱昂内尔 (Leonel)，我是 Tenente Esports 的马克西·迪洛 (Maxi Dilo)。
Leonel here, Maxi Dilo for Tenente Esports.
Leonel aquí, Maxi Dilo para Tenente Esports.
一个多月前...
A little over a month ago...
Hace poco más de un mes...
阿尔库迪亚锦标赛已经过去 6 年了。
6 years have passed since the Alcúdia tournament.
Se cumplieron 6 años del torneo de la Alcúdia.
我知道现在想起来很难，或许更广泛，但是……
I know that it is difficult to think about it now, perhaps it is more extensive, but...
Yo sé que por ahí es difícil ahora pensarlo, quizás es más extenso, pero...
您对这一步以及整个旅程有何看法？
What do you think about that step and the entire journey?
¿Qué pensás vos de aquel escalón y de todo el trayecto recorrido?
您对阿根廷足球与您目前的足球协会有何看法？
And what do you also think about that association of Argentine football with this one that you currently have?
¿Y qué pensás también de aquella asociación del fútbol argentino con esta que tenés en la actualidad?
起初我不知道那一年我在做什么，但是……
At first I didn't know what I was doing that year, but...
Primero no sabía que hacía ese año, pero...
时间对于每个人来说都在流逝
time passes for everyone
pasa el tiempo para todos
我喜欢看这些图像，因为当时我可能还是个孩子，而现在......
I like to see the images because I was probably a kid at that time and now...
que me gusta ver las imágenes porque seguramente sea un pibe en esa época y ahora...
我的意思是，我喜欢它。
I mean, I feel like it.
O sea, tengo ganas.
但本质本身并没有改变我的存在方式、我理解足球的方式、我与足球的联系方式。
But well, the essence itself has not changed my way of being at all, my way of understanding football, my way of relating to football.
Pero bueno, la esencia misma no ha cambiado absolutamente nada mi manera de ser, mi manera de entender el fútbol, mi manera de relacionarme con el fútbol.
与人们在一起，而不仅仅是与球员在一起，对我来说这是一次经历
with the people, not just with the players and for me it was an experience
con la gente, no sólo con los jugadores y para mí fue una experiencia
壮观，这是我经历过的最好的比赛之一，尽管这是一场锦标赛
Spectacular, one of the best I've had even though it was a tournament
espectacular, de las mejores que he tenido aunque haya sido un torneo
但如果我们可以称其为未被认可，那么对我们来说这是非常重要的。
but if we can call it unrecognized, for us it was very important.
pero si podemos llamarlo no reconocido, para nosotros fue importantísimo.
我把它留下了美好的回忆。
and I keep it with great memories.
y lo guardo con un enorme recuerdo.
对我来说，这是很多事情的开始。
For me it was the beginning of a lot of things.
Para mí fue el inicio de un montón de cosas.
另一个索引是 alpha
the other index is the alpha
el índice otro queda es el alfa
好吧，不管怎样，管理层总是一样的，我们周围的人总是一样的。
Well, anyway, the management is always the same, the people around us are always the same.
Bueno, igual, lo directiva siempre es la misma, la gente que está alrededor de nosotros siempre es la misma.
谢谢！
¡Gracias!
而一切都已经随着终极事物的构成而被放大，但本质……
and everything is already magnified with the constitution of the ultimate things, but the essence...
y ya todo magnificado con la constitución de las cosas últimas, pero la esencia...
他们的支持和支持都保持不变，所以我们改变了很多。
With them it remains the same and the support too, so we have changed a lot.
con ellos sigue siendo la misma y el apoyo también, así que hemos cambiado mucho.
加布里埃尔，你好吗？
Gabriel, how are you doing?
Gabriel, ¿cómo te va?
中午好，我将对其进行扩展，以便您感觉良好。
Good noon, I will expand on it so that it seems good to you.
Buen mediodía, te ampliaré para que les parezca bien.
我们还活着。
We are live.
Estamos en vivo.
你和迪玛利亚谈到了明天将在球场上与他一起致敬，你会喜欢吗？
You spoke with Di María about the tribute that will be given tomorrow being with him on the field, would you have liked that?
Hablaste con Di María acerca de que el homenaje que se va a hacer mañana sea con él en cancha, ¿tú hubieses gustado de eso?
让他好好发挥我说过了
let him play well I spoke
que se vaya jugando bueno yo hablé
我在拥抱中、在庆祝中说话。
I spoke in the hug, in the celebration.
Hablé en el abrazo, en el festejo.
第一个想法是让他在阿根廷踢最后一场比赛，但让他上场吧。
The first idea was for him to play the last game here in Argentina, but let him play.
La primera idea era que él juegue el último partido acá en Argentina, pero que juegue.
让他像最后一场比赛一样打球，但有必要的话。
Let him play as if it were a final match, but as much as necessary.
Que juegue como si fuera un partido final, pero todo lo que sea necesario.
我从来不打算让他打几分钟，因为在我看来……
It was never my idea for him to play a few minutes because it seems to me that...
Nunca fui la idea de que juegue unos minutos porque me parece que el...
这场比赛非常重要，值得这样看待。
the match is important enough to take it that way.
el partido es lo suficientemente importante como para tomarlo de esa manera.
然后稍后再考虑
then thinking about it later
entonces pensándolo bien después
我很巧合地在飞机上遇见了他，因为我们一起飞往...
I coincidentally met him on the plane because we flew together to...
casualmente lo encontré en el avión porque volamos juntos para...
对于西班牙，他与家人和孩子一起前往，但进展并不顺利......
For Spain, he went with his family and his children and it didn't go so well and...
para España, él iba con su familia y sus hijos y no se dio tan bien y...
喝完酒后就是这样，我本来想给他打电话，但我趁机在那里和他说话
After the drink it was this and well I was going to call him but I took the opportunity to talk to him there
después de la copa fue esto y bueno lo iba a llamar pero aproveché a hablarle ahí con él
并告诉他我们相信重要的是人们看到他说再见但在球场上
and to tell him that we believed that the important thing was that people see him say goodbye but that on the field
y a decirle que creíamos que lo importante era que la gente lo vea despedirse pero que adentro de la cancha
他们没有看到那 11,000 个人有可能做到人们所说的那样，因为在我看来……
They didn't see the possibility of those 11,000 do that people said, as it seemed to me that...
no veían con la posibilidad de esos 11.000 do que decía la gente, como me parecía que...
比赛很重要，对手也必须得到尊重。
The match is very important, the opponent must also be respected.
El partido es muy importante, el rival también hay que respetarlo.
这个想法从来没有真正出现在我的脑海中。
That idea was never really in my head.
Esa idea realmente en mi cabeza nunca estuvo.
是的，首先是我必须参加比赛。
Yes, the first was that I had to play.
Sí, la primera era que tenía que jugar.
作为一名球员所必需的分钟数更像是最近的。
the minutes that are necessary as a player more like it was recently.
los minutos que sean necesarios como jugador más como fue hace poco.
但与他交谈时他告诉我，看，他已经很清楚他的......
But talking to him he told me, look, he was already clear that his...
pero hablándolo con él me dijo, mirá, él ya tenía clara que su...
球队已经完成了决赛，这一点非常清楚。
The team had finished the final, it was very clear.
La selección había terminado la final, lo tenía clarísimo.
在那里我们意识到这对每个人来说都是最好的。
And there we realized that it was the best for everyone.
Y ahí nos dimos cuenta de que era lo mejor para todos.
这是一个电影的结局，这是一个结局......
It was a movie ending, it was an ending...
Ha sido un final de película, ha sido un final...
老实说，如果你必须这样做
Honestly, if you have to do it
que sinceramente si uno lo tiene que hacer
在结果不太好之前
before they don't turn out so well
antes no les sale tan bien
太壮观了，我认为结果再好不过了。
Spectacular, I think it couldn't have turned out better.
Espectacular, yo creo que mejor no puede haber salido.
你好吗？
How are you?
¿Cómo estás?
问问自己，关于里奥，关于梅西，在受伤的这段时间里，他是否遭受了足够的痛苦
Ask yourself about Leo, about Messi, if in all this time of the injury he suffered enough
Preguntarte por Leo, por Messi, si en todo este tiempo de la lesión que sufrió bastante
他们脚踝受伤，仍在康复中
they hurt their ankle, they are still recovering
se venan el tobillo, todavía los tiene recuperándose
你说话了，如果你有了解，他显然会跟进，但知道他是怎样的，你从远处看他是怎样的。
You spoke, if you have understanding he obviously follows up, but knowing how he is, how you see him from a distance.
Hablaste, si tenés comprensión obviamente le hace un seguimiento, pero saber cómo está, cómo lo ven ustedes desde la distancia.
如果你已经知道下个月就能得到它......
If you already know that you will be able to have it next month...
Si ya sabés que lo vas a poder tener el próximo mes...
以及对泳池和阿古纳斯回报的反思。
and also the reflection on the returns in the pool and agunas.
y también la reflexión sobre los regresos en el piscina y agunas.
阿根廷足球显然在之前的市场上发生了很大的变化。
to Argentine football that obviously moved a lot here in the previous market.
al fútbol argentino que obviamente movieron mucho acá en el mercado anterior.
在学校我讲过
At school I spoke
En el colegio hablé
在给出清单之前亲自看看它怎么样并且......
personally before giving the list to see how it was and...
personalmente antes de dar la lista para ver cómo estaba y...
从逻辑上讲，我一直在训练他，而他还很早熟。
Logically, I had been training him and he was very premature.
Lógicamente lo venía entrenando y era muy prematuro.
错误地，它还没有准备好，所以他告诉我它正在变得更好
By mistake it's not ready so he told me it was getting better
por error no está lista así que me dijo que iba mejorando
他能和球队一起比赛只是时间问题，所以这取决于他这几天能否上场。
It is a matter of time before he can play with his team, so it will depend on whether he plays these days.
Es cuestión de tiempo de que pueda jugar con su equipo, así que dependerá de si juega en estos días.
下一个电话也很快了，所以...
the next call is soon too, so...
la siguiente convocatoria que es dentro de poco también, así que...
这就是谈话。
That was the conversation.
Esa fue la conversación.
我从德国和马科斯那里把它还回来，嗯，首先
And I return it from Germán and Marcos, well, first
Y lo regreso de Germán y de Marcos, bueno, primero
阿根廷足球的等级制度是因为除了球员之外还有球员
hierarchy in Argentine soccer because it is the players in addition to
jerarquiza en el fútbol argentino pues son los jugadores además de
世界冠军是两名球员，他们是
world champions are two players and the guys who
campeones del mundo son dos jugadores y los tipos que
他们做得很好，我们祝他们一切顺利。
They have done things very well and we wish them the best.
que han hecho las cosas muy bien y le deseamos lo mejor.
我总是说我们不在乎他们要去哪里比赛，从逻辑上讲，如果他们来自阿根廷
I always say that we don't care where they are going to play, logically if they come from Argentina
Siempre digo que no nos importa donde van a jugar, lógicamente si vienen de Argentina
这对每个人都更好，因为它来自我们的国家。
It is better for everyone because it comes from our country.
Es mejor para todos porque viene de nuestro país.
他们在一个为了事情而争吵的俱乐部里，所以......
They're in a club that fights over things, so...
Están en un club que pelea por cosas, así que...
这些电话总是基于我们认为团队需要的内容。
The calls are always based on what we believe the team needs.
Las convocatores siempre están en base a lo que creemos que le hace falta de equipo.
莱昂纳多·皮罗蒂（Leonardo Pirotti），来自《观察家广播电台》（Radio El Ospectador），作者：Rafaela
Leonardo Pirotti, from Radio El Espectador, by Rafaela
Leonardo Pirotti, de Radio El Espectador, de Rafaela
近期无集中比赛无冠军的好时光
good time without concentrated competition without championships in the near future
bien tiempo sin competencia concentrada sin campeonatos en los próximos tiempos
作为团队领导者，您有什么想法？
What do you have in mind as a team leader?
¿Qué tienen pensado que tener pensado como jefe de equipo?
利用这段时间进行一些修改，思考变体。
Use this time to make some modifications, to think about variants.
utilizar este tiempo para hacer alguna modificación, para pensar en variantes.
从战术角度来看，这是一个和另一个，如果你能留下你的想法的话。
From a tactical point of view, that is one and the other, if you can leave a line of what you thought.
desde el punto de vista táctico, esa es una y la otra, si podés dejar una línea de qué te pareció.
Supa XIII 在奥运会上的展示。
the presentation of the Supa XIII at the Olympic Games.
la presentación del Supa XIII en los Juegos Olímpicos.
谢谢。
Gracias.
想象一下十一月之后的失业情况。
The unemployment after November, imagine.
El parante después de noviembre, imagínate.
因为现在球队很好，我认为我们不必考虑
because right now the team is good and I don't think we have to think about
porque ahora mismo el equipo está bien y no creo que haya que pensar en
尽管我们不断地寻找、分析，但我认为团队......
Although we are continually looking, analyzing, I think the team...
aunque estamos continuamente mirando, analizando, creo que el equipo...
很好，这个团队的伟大之处在于
is good and that the great virtue that this team has is that
está bien y que la gran virtud que tiene este equipo es que
每个人都知道他们在玩什么并且现在
that everyone knows what they are playing and that for now
que todo el mundo sabe a lo que juega y que por ahora
改变一下是好事，也许不合适，但是……
A change would be good, maybe it wouldn't be appropriate, but...
un cambio sería bueno, a lo mejor no sería oportuno, pero sí que...
我们正在不断分析，这也在很大程度上取决于最终出场的球员。
that we are continually analyzing and it will also depend a lot on the players who come out.
que estamos continuamente analizando y dependerá mucho también de los jugadores que vayan saliendo
他们可以给我们一些东西，或者他们可以给我们一些不同的东西，让他加入或不加入球队。
They can give us things or they can give us something different in putting him on the team or not.
nos pueden aportar cosas o pueden aportarnos algo diferente en ponerlo en el equipo o no.
阿根廷队参加的最好的比赛是对阵法国队。
and Argentina's participation in the best match which was against France.
y la participación de Argentina en el mejor partido que fue contra Francia.
我认为它应该通过，它被淘汰了，它就在......的门口。
I think it deserved to pass, it was eliminated and it was at the gates of...
creo que mereció pasar quedó eliminada y estuvo a las puertas de...
赢得奖牌，尊重比赛的本质
to win a medal, respecting the essence of the game has had
de traerse una medalla, respetando la esencia de juego ha tenido
非常好的一段话，对现在来的这些人的呼吁是因为我们想要他们
very good passage and the call for these guys who have come now is because we want them
pasaje muy bueno y la convocatoria de estos chicos que han venido ahora es porque queremos que
他们可以为我们做出贡献，所以我认为......
that they can contribute to us, so I think that...
que nos pueden aportar a nosotros, así que yo creo que...
你并不总是需要赢得胜利才能把事情做好，这是你的第 23 次胜利，嗯......
You don't always have to win to do things well and this is your 23rd, well...
No siempre hay que ganar para hacer las cosas bien y este es su 23, bueno...
已经表明，即使在困难中，因为它经历了超过令人难以置信的困难......
has shown that even in difficulty, because it has had more than incredible difficulty to...
ha demostrado que aún en dificultad, porque ha tenido más que una dificultad increíble para...
组建你的团队
to form your team
para formar su equipo
奥运会的选拔以及俱乐部的拒绝等等，我仍然认为
a selection for the Olympic Games with the rejections of the clubs and all that, I still think that
una selección para unos Juegos Olímpicos con los rechazos de los clubes y todo eso, aún así creo que
下午好，来自智利电视台的罗伯托·普埃瓦斯。
Good afternoon, Roberto Puevas from TVN de Chile.
Buenas tardes, Roberto Puevas de TVN de Chile.
谁配得上你，或者你对需要积分的智利队有何看法？
Who deserves you or what do you think of the Chilean team, in need of points?
¿Quién te merece o qué piensa del equipo chileno, necesitado de puntos?
很年轻，没有多少人物
very young, without many figures
muy joven, sin muchas figuras
两者都以加速持续时间命名，这次被里卡多·加莱坎囚禁。
both named for as long as the acceleration lasted and this time imprisoned by Ricardo Galecán.
tanto nombrada por tanto tiempo como la aceleración durada y esta vez encarcelada por Ricardo Galecán.
第一个想到的是一支踢得好的球队。
The first one that comes to mind is a team that plays football well.
El primero que me viene a la cabeza es un equipo que juega bien al fútbol.
他的教练总是灌输他要踢好足球，而且……
His coach always instills in him to play football well and...
su entrenador siempre le inculca jugar bien el fútbol y...
从我看来，他正在经历一段……
and from what I see he is going through a moment of...
y por lo que veo está atravesando un momento de...
我认为是积极的变化。
of change that I think is positive.
de cambio que creo que es positivo.
我们祝他一切顺利，里卡多一直对我们说得很好。
We wish him the best, Ricardo has always had a very good word with us.
Le deseamos lo mejor, Ricardo siempre ha tenido palabra muy buena con nosotros.
从你所看到的来看，他是一个会轻松行事、让球员发挥的人。
He is a guy who, from what you can see, will go easy, let the player play.
Es un tipo que, por lo que se ve, irá de tranquilidad, deja jugar al jugador.
历史上，智利一直是我们的难敌。
Chile has always been a difficult rival for us historically.
Chile siempre ha sido un rival para nosotros difícil históricamente.
明天也是如此，所以我致以最崇高的敬意。
and it will be tomorrow too, so with the utmost respect.
y lo será también mañana, así que con máximo respeto.
我们将以最好的方式面对比赛，对抗一个......
We will confront the game in the best way, against a rival who...
La confrontaremos al partido de la mejor manera, ante un rival que...
无论他需要与否，他一直都具有竞争力。
that beyond the points he needs or not he has always been competitive.
que más allá de los puntos que necesite o no siempre ha sido competitivo.
怎么样了？
How's it going?
¿Cómo te va?
第一，教练组内当然对你来说是一个很大的挑战
the first and within the coaching staff of course it is a great challenge for you
las primeras y dentro del cuerpo técnico por supuesto es un gran desafío para ustedes
事实上，至少在前两场比赛中，无论是没有梅西，还是有迪玛利亚，两人中的一个总是在一起。
The fact of living together, at least in these first two games, both without Messi and with Di María, one of the two was always there.
El hecho de convivir, al menos en estos dos primeros partidos, tanto sin Messi como con Di María, siempre alguno de los dos estaba.
另一个人说加雷卡最好不要动摇，他有一个勇敢的后卫，即将退役，桑切斯受伤了，亚历克西斯更好
and the other said Gareca that it was better that they were not rocked, he has a brave back who is retiring and Sánchez is injured, Alexis is better
y la otra dijo Gareca que era mejor que no estén mecidas, tiene el espaldao bravo que se retira y sánchez lesionado, Alexis es mejor
教练组不是挑战，相反，我们是
The coaching staff is not a challenge, on the contrary, we are
el cuerpo técnico no es que sea un reto al contrario nosotros estamos
当我们在国家队时，我们可以为那里的男孩们提供帮助。
When we are in the national team we are available to the boys who are there.
cuando estamos en la selección estamos a disposición de los chicos que estén.
从逻辑上讲，他们两个不是一个人，总是很奇怪。
Logically, it is always strange that the two of them are not one.
Lógicamente siempre es extraño que no estén uno ellos dos.
但是，嘿，这就是我们现在所做的。
But hey, that's what we do now.
Pero bueno, es lo que toca ahora.
我们需要每个人都向前迈出一小步，因为他们不在那里并表明......
and we need everyone to take that little step forward because they are not there and show that...
y necesitamos que todos den ese pasito adelante porque no están ellos y demostrar que...
我们一定会完成这场比赛的任务。
We will be up to the task of this match.
estaremos a la altura de este partido.
至于布拉沃、亚历克西斯的伤亡……
And as for the casualties of Bravo, of Alexis...
Y en cuanto a las bajas de Bravo, de Alexis...
他们是球员，我不需要说，他们在国家队创造了历史，并且已经成为国家队的一员。
They are players, I don't need to say it, who have made history in their national team and who have been
Son jugadores, no hace falta que lo diga yo, que han hecho historia en su selección y que han sido
为了全球发展。
for global development.
para el desarrollo mundial.
他们不在那里总是更好，这一点很明显，因为他们是令人难以置信的球员，但是哦，好吧。
It is always better that they are not there, that is clear because they are incredible players, but oh well.
Siempre mejor que no estén, eso está claro porque son unos jugadores increíbles, pero bueno.
总是一样的事情，足球是如此奇怪，最终你永远无法相信它，智利也不再是这样了。
The same thing always, football is so strange that in the end you can never trust it and it's not like Chile is any more of that.
Lo mismo siempre, el fútbol es tan extraño que al final nunca te puedes confiar y no es que Chile sea más de eso.
因为我没有他们两个，但很明显他们是两个伟大的球员。
because I don't have the two of them, but it is evident that they are two great players.
porque no tengo ellos dos, pero sí es evidente que son dos grandes jugadores.
洛伦，埃尔纳诺·多梅尼科·洛罗萨，那位打断自己的话的同事。
Llorén, Hernano Domenico Llorosa, the colleague who interrupted himself.
Llorén, Hernano Domenico Llorosa, el compañero que se interrumpió.
到目前为止，您对第一轮预选赛以及本轮预选赛的总体情况有何分析？
What analysis do you make so far of this first round of qualifying rounds, of this round of qualifying rounds in general?
¿Qué análisis haces hasta ahora de esta primera fecha de eliminatorias, de esta marcha de eliminatorias en general?
以及厄瓜多尔现在需要的阿根廷教练数量，古斯塔沃
and the number of Argentine coaches that are now required in Ecuador, Gustavo
y de la cantidad de entrenadores argentinos que hay requeridos ahora en Ecuador, Gustavo
是的，好吧，我不知道这是否是最受欢迎的季节，但是......
Yes, well, I don't know if it's the most popular season but...
Sí, bueno, yo no sé si es la época que más hay pero...
上一轮也有不少人，我们已经输了，有多少人？
There were also quite a few in the previous round and we already lost, how many are there?
La anterior eliminatoria también había bastantes y ya perdimos, ¿cuántos hay?
七对七？
Seven against seven?
¿Siete contra siete?
6 又多又好
6 are many and good
6 son muchos y bueno
就是要讲得好，让人们看到自己的反映，或者看到阿根廷教练的工作。
It is to speak well and for people to see themselves reflected or see the work of the Argentine coaches.
Es para hablar bien y que la gente se vea reflejada o vea el trabajo de los entrenadores argentinos.
所以对我们来说这非常好，我希望他们做得很好
So for us it is very good and I hope they do well
Así que para nosotros es muy bueno y ojalá les vaya bien
有一只鸡半，希望我们都去世界杯，那就太好了。
There is a chicken and a half, I hope we all go to the World Cup, which would be very good.
hay un pollo y medio, ojalá vayamos todos al Mundial, que sería muy bueno.
你好吗，莱昂内尔？
How are you, Leonel?
¿Qué tal, Leonel?
早上好。
Good morning.
Buenos días.
莫妮卡·瓦莱拉（Mónica Valera），代表独特的团队。
Mónica Valera, for the unique team.
Mónica Valera, por el equipo único.
我想问你两个问题。
I want to ask you two questions.
Te quiero hacer dos consultas.
首先，你刚才提到了九月约会的不舒服。
The first, you just said about the discomfort of the September date.
La primera, recién decías de la incomodidad de la fecha de septiembre.
三名球员改变了俱乐部，超越了他们的个人和个人成长。
and three players have changed clubs, beyond their personal and individual growth.
y tres jugadores han cambiado de club, más allá de su crecimiento personal e individual.
由于教练的更换以及这些俱乐部的训练方式的变化，这也令人感到不舒服。
It is also uncomfortable because of the change of coaches, the change in training that those clubs have.
Es también incómodo por el cambio de entrenadores, el cambio de entrenamientos que tienen de esos clubes.
关于阿根廷国家队，我想问你的另一件事是关于你所看到的阿根廷联赛
regarding the Argentine national team and the other thing I want to ask you is regarding the Argentine league as you are seeing it
en cuanto a la selección argentina y la otra que te quiero hacer es en cuanto a la liga argentina como la estás viendo
与通常不在积分榜前列的球队竞争。
competitive with teams that are not usually at the top of the table.
competitiva con equipos que habitualmente no están arriba de la tabla.
谢谢。
Gracias.
关于其他俱乐部的球员变动，
Regarding player changes to other clubs,
En cuanto a los cambios de jugadores a otros clubes,
改变我们的并不是那么多
it's not so much what changes us
no es tanto lo que nos cambia
如果不是时候，他们可能已经去了另一个俱乐部，他们的……
They may have gone to another club if it's not time, their...
que se hayan ido a otro club sino es el momento, recién están llegando sus...
新俱乐部正在了解他们的教练同事
new clubs are getting to know their fellow coaches
nuevos clubes están conociendo a sus compañeros entrenadores
有些还没有玩过，可能会影响我们，但在一段时间内
some have not played yet that can affect us but within a
algunos todavía no han jugado eso sí que nos puede afectar pero dentro de un
两三个月，那将是......
two or three months and that will be a...
dos o tres meses y ya eso será un...
不是故事，但现在是了，现在仍然不舒服。
not a story, but now it is, now it is still uncomfortable.
una historia que no, pero ahora sí, ahora sí que no deja de ser incómodo.
阿根廷锦标赛的竞争非常激烈。
The Argentine championship is very competitive.
El campeonato argentino es muy competitivo.
我认为贝莱斯现在正在经历一个伟大的时刻并且正在进球......
I think Vélez is going through a great moment now and is scoring...
Creo que Vélez ahora está atravesando un gran momento y está marcando...
有点不同，Huracan 也不错。
A little difference, Huracán was good too.
Un poquito la diferencia, Huracán estaba bien también.
我认为Beresoy做得很好，方向也相当明确。
I think Beresoy is doing well, with a fairly clear direction.
Creo que Beresoy está bien, con un rumbo bastante claro.
而其他队伍则在后面追赶，试图阻止他逃跑。
and the other teams chasing behind, trying to keep him from escaping.
y los demás equipos persiguiendo atrás, intentando que no se escape.
足球一直都是这样，好处是有很多球队。
Football has always been like this and the good thing is that there are many teams there.
El fútbol tiene siempre sido así y lo bueno es que hay muchos equipos ahí.
就在那里，直到最后。
up there and it will be until the end.
ahí arriba y va a ser hasta el final.
我们希望人们喜欢它。
We hope people enjoy it.
Esperamos que la gente lo disfrute.
莱昂内尔，我们将为电台进行编辑，不客气，我们正在直播。
Leonel, we'll edit it for the radio and you're welcome, we're live.
Leonel, más se le editaremos para la radio y ya de nada, estamos en vivo.
问你关于男生的话题，因为你的素材太多了……
ask you about the topic of boys, because you have so much material...
preguntarte sobre el tema de los chicos, porque tenés tanto material...
很多，有时可能很难说谁是首发。
a lot, that sometimes it may be difficult to have to say who is the starter.
mucho, que a veces quizás se dificulta tener que decir quiénes van de titular.
但这也让你很容易说，好吧，我对未来有很多思考。
but it also makes it very easy for you to say, well, I have plenty of material thinking about the future.
pero también te da mucha facilidad para decir, bueno tengo material de sobra pensando en el futuro.
您如何看待这种情况，如何处理？
How are you seeing that situation, how are you handling it?
¿Cómo vas viendo esa situación, cómo la vas manejando?
考虑下一个立法日期，也考虑这个和下一个，对吧？
Thinking about the next legislative dates, thinking about this one and the next ones too, right?
pensando en las próximas fechas de legislatoria, pensando en esta y en las próximas también, ¿no?
好吧，多余的材料永远不会更好，越多越好，我们想要......
Well, excess material is never better, the more the better, we want...
Bueno, el material de sobra nunca es mejor, que cuanto más haya mejor, queremos que...
这是积极的，因为它提高了竞争力水平，同事们不会放松。
That is positive because it raises the level of competitiveness and colleagues are not going to relax.
Eso es positivo porque alcha el nivel de competitividad y los compañeros no se van a relajar.
嗯，正如我之前所说，我认为...
Well, and what I said before, I think...
Bueno, y lo que dije antes, creo...
他们将根据我们创造的内容进入或发挥作用。
They are going to enter or play based on what we create.
van a entrar o jugar en base a lo que creamos.
对于国家队来说幸运的是，球队有他们的基地不不不
Luckily for the national team the team has a base for them no no no
por suerte para la selección el equipo tiene una base para ellos no no no
它不是那么积极，因为有的分钟或位置
It is not so positive because the minutes or positions in which there are are
no es tan positivo porque los minutos o las posiciones en las que hay son
机会很少，我们会尽力为我们相信的人提供机会
There are very few and we will try to give the opportunity to whoever we believe in a moment
son muy pocas e intentaremos dar la oportunidad a quien creamos en un momento
但有时只是训练、和教练一起看视频......
But sometimes it's just that training, watching a video with the coach...
Pero a veces es que el entrenar, el ver un video con el entrenador...
在一起也能做很多事情，但不一定非得如此
Being together also does a lot, which does not necessarily have to be
el estar junto también hace un montón, que no necesariamente tiene que estar
周四在球场上，这样我们就能看到他在训练中能给我们带来什么，我们也看到了一些东西
on the field on Thursday so that we can see what he can give us in training, we also see things and
dentro de la cancha el jueves para que nosotros veamos lo que nos puede dar en los entrenamientos también vemos cosas y
当然，如果你明天没有机会，以后就会有机会，但重要的是你们一起努力。
Surely if you don't have the opportunity tomorrow you will have it later, but the important thing is that you work together.
Seguramente si no tiene la oportunidad mañana la tendrá más adelante, pero lo importante es que se vayan acuplando.
你好吗？
How are you?
¿Cómo estás?
再会。
Good day.
Buen día.
卡洛斯·弗雷戈西为《今日阵容》。
Carlos Fregosi for The Squad of the Day.
Carlos Fregosi para La Escuadra del Día.
他们知道我为 2050 年布宜诺斯艾利斯广播电台而活。
They know I live for Radio Buenos Aires, year 2050.
Conocen vivo para Radio Buenos Aires, año 2050.
周一，我们与卢卡斯·卡斯特罗曼进行了交谈，谈论了他，并向他询问了您正在领导的流程，他说
On Monday we spoke with Lucas Castromán and talking about him and asking him precisely about the process that you are leading, he said that
el lunes hablamos con Lucas Castromán y hablando de él y preguntándole justamente por el proceso que estás encabezando, él dijo que
这是世界足坛最好的故事，我觉得它可能会让你有点不舒服。
It is the best story in world football, I feel that it may leave you a little uncomfortable.
es la mejor historia del fútbol mundial te siento que te puede dejar un poco incómodo
分析机器人，但我希望你站在外面一点分析这个，给医生喝两杯......
Analyze the robot, but I would like you to stand a little outside and analyze this, two drinks to the doctor...
analiza el robot, pero me gustaría que te pongas un poquito de afuera y analíces esto, dos copas a médica...
非常精致的现代德国风格，时隔多年的世界杯。
a very fine modern German style, a world cup after so many years.
una finaísima alemándola modernitaria, una copa de mundos después de tantos años.
我们把它放在哪里？
Where do we put?
¿Dónde ponemos?
如果我们打开该进程，它们会留在哪里？
Where are they left if we turn on the process?
¿A dónde quedan si encendimos el proceso?
2019 年，阿奎萨·科波拉 (Arquisa Coppola) 和传统美国以及我的同事们正式亮相。
officially Arquisa Coppola and conventional America and my colleagues in 2019.
oficialmente Arquisa Coppola y América convencionales y mis colegas en 2019.
我首先感谢卢卡这么说。
I thank Luca first for saying that.
Agradezco a Luca primero por haber dicho eso.
嗯，我不能告诉你...
Well, I couldn't tell you...
Bueno, no sabría decirte...
我也不是一个会分析我们应该在哪里、我们现在在哪里的人……
I'm also not one to analyze where we should be, where we are...
Tampoco soy de analizar en dónde tendríamos que estar, dónde estamos...
这是一个非常甜蜜的时刻。
It was a very sweet moment.
Fue un momento muy dulce.
几年前，也许没有人考虑过这个问题，或者至少很难考虑。
Years ago maybe no one thought about it or at least it was difficult to think about.
años atrás a lo mejor ninguno lo pensaba o por lo menos era difícil de pensar.
所有这一切的重要一点是，事情是可以做的，可以实现的。
The important thing about all this is that things can be done, they can be achieved.
Lo importante de todo esto es que se pueden hacer las cosas, se pueden conseguir.
我认为这就是我们要拯救的
and I think that is what we rescue
y eso creo que es lo que nosotros rescatamos
尤其是如果有任何时候你肯定会遇到困难的时刻
and especially if there is any time you will surely come to a difficult time
y sobre todo si hay algún momento que seguramente vendrán a un momento difícil
他已经准备好了，他已经准备好站起来，回到……
He's ready for that, he's ready to get up and get back to...
está preparado para eso, está preparado para levantarse y volver a...
尝试正如许多人所展示的那样。
to try as many of these guys have shown.
a intentarlo como han demostrado muchísimos de estos chicos.
我认为最终我们必须停止这种做法，思考我们现在所处的位置。
and I think that in the end that is what we have to stop, thinking about where we are.
y yo creo que al final eso es lo que tenemos que dejar, pensar en qué puesto estamos.
不幸的是，过去的已经过去了，而且这种情况仍在继续。
The past is unfortunately the past and this continues.
Lo pasado lamentablemente el pasado está y esto sigue.
最终他们将留在统计数据中，那些喜欢看到这一点的人将留在历史中。
In the end they will remain in the statistics, those who like to see this will remain in history.
al final quedarán en la estadística, quedarán en la historia a los que les gusta ver esto.
但我们已经在这里，我们必须继续前进，我们不能就此安眠。
But we are here and we have to continue, we cannot sleep on that.
Pero nosotros estamos acá y tenemos que seguir, no nos podemos dormir en eso.
对我们来说，人民就足够了
and it was enough for us that the people
y nos bastó con que la gente
感到高兴并认为这个团队可以继续给予我们所有人想要的快乐。
Be happy and think that this team can continue giving the joy that is what we all want.
esté feliz y esté pensando en que este equipo pueda seguir dando la alegría que es lo que todos queremos.
最后两个问题。
Last two questions.
Últimas dos preguntas.
米格尔，下午好，我们要失明了。
Miguel, good afternoon, we are going to be blind.
Miguel, buenas tardes, vamos a estar ciego.
首先，我将咨询瓦伦丁·卡尔博尼（Valentín Carboni），他是这次电话会议中最年轻的。
First I am going to consult with Valentín Carboni, who is the youngest in this call.
Primero voy a consultarte con Valentín Carboni, que es el más joven de esta convocatoria.
正是在听到迭戈·弗兰戈杀了他之后，我想到了这个触发点
and precisely this trigger comes to me after having heard Diego Frango killing him
y justamente este disparador me surge después de haber escuchado a Diego Frango matándolo
17岁的时候他说他有点怀念以前的生活。
at 17 years old saying that he misses his old life a little bit.
con 17 años diciendo que extraña un poquito su vieja vida.
不被人注意，做任何男孩都能做的事情。
that of going unnoticed and doing the things that any boy can do.
esa de pasar desapercibido y hacer las cosas que puede hacer cualquier chico.
那个年龄，同时他们是否在运动心理学方面支持你
of that age and at the same time if they support you a lot in sports psychology
de esa edad y paralelamente si te apoyan mucho en la psicología del deporte
以科学的荣耀等
in the glory of science, etc.
en la gloria de ciencia, etc.
或者如果你和孩子们聊了很多。
or if you talk a lot with the kids.
o si hablás mucho vos con los chicos.
以便他们在面对煽动国家的呼声时更加坚定。
so that they are more grounded in the face of the call for, precisely, the sedition of their country.
para que por ahí estén más con los pies en la tierra ante la convocatoria de, justamente, la sedición de su país.
这是最困难的，因为他们还是孩子。
It is the most difficult because they are still children.
es lo más difícil porque son nenes todavía
他们发现自己陷入了困境
they find themselves in a situation
se encuentran en una situación
我们都曾在某个时刻，没有达到加蓬的水平，从逻辑上讲，我的水平要低得多，但是是的......
We have all been at some point, not at the level of Gabon and I logically much less so, but yes...
Todos hemos estado en algún momento, no a la altura de Gabón y yo lógicamente mucho menos, pero sí que...
当我有那个...
When I had that...
Cuando tenía esa...
但在打击乐中你确实面临着混淆的风险
but in percussion you do run the risk of getting confused
pero en percusiones sí que corres el riesgo de confundirte
你试图通过与他们、你自己的同事交谈来防止这种情况发生在他们身上......
and you try to prevent that from happening to them by talking to them, your own colleagues...
y uno intenta de que eso no les pase hablándoles, sus propios compañeros...
好吧，一切都得到了改善，并且有更多工具可以防止这种情况发生
well say you, everything has improved and there are many more tools to prevent that from happening
bien decir vos, todo ha mejorado y hay muchas más herramientas para que eso no suceda
他们是突然间一切都落在他们身上的孩子。
They are kids who have everything suddenly fallen on them.
Son chicos que le ha caído todo de repente.
重要的是，他们知道自己只是足球运动员，仅此而已，这就是我们最后总是试图告诉他们的
and it is important that they know that they are just soccer players and nothing more, that is what we always try to tell them in the end
y es importante que sepan que solo son jugadores de fútbol y nada más eso es lo que siempre intentamos decirles al final
只不过是踢足球，你无法相信比踢足球更重要的事情，当
are nothing more than playing football, you cannot believe more than playing football and when
no son más que jugar el fútbol no se puede creer más que jugar el fútbol y cuando
他们还年轻，也许有人能让你相信。
They are young, maybe someone can make you believe it.
Son jóvenes, a lo mejor alguno te lo puede hacer creer.
当你到了一定的年纪，他们很难让你相信这一点，因为你经历了很多事情。
When you are of a certain age it is difficult for them to make you believe it because you went through a lot of things.
Ya cuando tenés una cierta edad es difícil que te lo hagan creer porque pasaste muchas cosas.
但当你年轻的时候，重要的是...
But when you are young it is important that...
Pero cuando sos joven es importante que...
他周围的每个人，他的同事，他的家人，他周围的人，让他明白
that everyone around him, his colleagues, his family, the people around him, make him understand
que todo el entorno, sus compañeros, su familia, la gente que está alrededor se lo haga entender
继续像三四年前在酒吧踢足球一样踢足球，就马斯坦托诺而言，我也给了他这个例子。
Keep playing soccer like you played 3 or 4 years ago in the bar and soccer, in the case of Mastantono I also gave him this example.
siga jugando al fútbol como jugaba hace 3 o 4 años en el bar y fútbol, en el caso de Mastantono también que le puse este ejemplo.
重要的是，他们不要失去本质并将自己与这一切隔离开来，但他们周围的人......
It is important that they do not lose that essence and isolate themselves from all that, but the people around them are...
Es importante que no pierdan esa esencia y que se aíslen de todo eso, pero la gente que está alrededor es...
让他们明白自己只不过是足球运动员，这一点至关重要。
It is essential to make them understand that they are nothing more than soccer players.
Es fundamental hacerle entender que no son más que jugadores de fútbol.
他们无法解决任何人的生活，他们也不会这样做，他们唯一要做的就是周日外出时
They cannot solve anyone's life and they are not going to do it, the only thing they are going to do is on Sunday when they go out
no pueden solucionar la vida de nadie y no lo van a hacer, lo único que van a hacer es el domingo cuando salgan
在球场上，尽力做到最好，享受美好时光，从那里发生的事情并不取决于他们。
on the court, try to do your best, have a good time and from there what happens does not depend on them.
en la cancha, intentar dar lo mejor, pasarla bien y a partir de ahí lo que pasa no depende de ellos.
福克斯体育。
for Fox Sports.
para Fox Sports.
我想问你关于朱利安·阿尔瓦雷斯的事。
I want to ask you about Julián Álvarez.
Te quiero preguntar por Julián Álvarez.
他决定换俱乐部，你刚才谈到了科坦。
He decided to change clubs, you talked a little while ago about Cortan.
Decidió cambiar de club, hablaste hace un ratito del Cortán.
以及这可能如何改变当今的工作方式。
and how this perhaps changes work these days.
y de cómo esto modifica quizás el trabajo en estos días.
你对他来到马德里竞技寻求连续性和所有权并离开像马德里这样重要的球队有何看法？
What do you think of his arrival at Atlético Madrid seeking continuity and ownership and leaving a team as important as Madrid?
¿Qué te parece su llegada al Atlético Madrid buscando continuidad y titularidad y saliendo de un equipo tan importante como el Madrid?
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
好吧，其他答案的路线是个人决定。
Well, the line of the other answers are personal decisions.
Bueno, la línea de las otras respuestas son decisiones personales.
他离开了一个伟大的俱乐部去了另一个俱乐部。
He has left a great club to go to another.
Ha dejado un gran club por irse a otro.
俱乐部，希望一切顺利，这很好
club and let's hope it goes well and that's good
club y esperemos que le vaya bien y que bueno
如果他一切顺利，国家队也会一切顺利，但事实是，这个决定是个人的，
If things go well for him, things will go well for the national team, but the truth is that the decision has been personal and
si le va bien a él le va a ir bien a la selección pero la decisión la verdad que ha sido personal y
在这种情况下，我们不参与其中，所以这是可能的。
and in this case we don't get involved, so that is possible.
y en este caso no nos metemos, así que eso es posible.
谢谢。
Gracias.